Cindy Chiang

626-376-3277 cindyc@usc.edu https://cindy-chiang.github.io/ www.linkedin.com/in/cindy-chiang1

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I research how people think about language through behavioral experiments and analysis of naturalistic interactions. I collaborate with psychologists, linguists, and computer scientists to better understand how different interactions, including interactions with technology, impact the language children and adults expect and produce.

EDUCATION

University of Southern California

Ph.D in Psychology and Minor in Quantitative Methods

Los Angeles, California August 2016-May 2022

Smith College Northampton, Massachusetts

Bachelor in Psychology 2010-2013

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Southern California

Graduate Researcher in the Department of Psychology

Los Angeles, California August 2016-Present

- Finance and manage multi-disciplinary projects with grants from the National Science Foundation (NSF) and USC
- Conceptualize, design, and collect data for 7 lines of primary research with infants, children, and adults and 3 lines of secondary research with recordings and annotations of conversations in natural settings
- Utilize in lab and online eye-tracking to examine effects of attention, memory, and cognitive control on abilities to detect patterns and process speech in 350+ children
- Conduct usability test to improve mouse-tracking study (click test) used by 350+ adults, generating millions of data points
- Program unmoderated online card sort task to investigate 150+ children's growing understanding of concepts
- Evaluate web logs and recordings of 300+ unmoderated study sessions to detect software bug on online experiment platform used by 600+ developmental psychologists
- Collaborate with cross-functional team of psychologists and computer scientists to understand how verbal interactions with computers differ across 100+ school aged children and teenagers
- Analyze quantitative and qualitative datasets using Bayesian, frequentist, robust, and big data techniques with R
- Synthesize and present findings in 8 internationally attended conferences and 2 first author conference proceedings

Massachusetts General Hospital

Boston, Massachusetts

Clinical Research Coordinator I and II

January 2015-March 2016

- Analyzed over 75,000 patients records as well as hundreds of survey and interview responses using SPSS and STATA to investigate validity of early screening practices and preventative models of care
- Communicated findings in 2 internationally attended conferences and 3 peer-reviewed publications

Smith College

Northampton, Massachusetts

January 2011-May 2013

- Research Assistant/ Independent Researcher
- Investigated 144 Taiwanese preschoolers' language development leading to 1 first author conference presentation
- Performed ethnographic coding of social interactions between autistic children and their parents

ADDITIONAL RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Supply Chain Coordinator and Product Developer

Jowett Group

Los Angeles, California

January 2014-December 2014

- Streamlined manufacturing line to meet trend forecasts of Nike and Under Armour (over 450,000 pieces per month)
- Refined apparel design with design team and manufacturing floor to meet desired aesthetics and production costs

SKILLS

- Statistical Programs and Programming Languages R, SPSS, Stata, JavaScript, HTML, Python, LaTeX
- Software Adobe Photoshop, Praat, PyGaze, PsychoPy, OpenSesame, Microsoft Suite (VBA, Macro Programming)
- Languages English (Native); Chinese/ Mandarin (Native)